birst.com 2015-09-07

# Privacy Policy - Birst

#### Last Updated: August 31, 2015.

Birst Inc. is committed to customer privacy. This Privacy Policy communicates our customer information gathering and dissemination practices. This Privacy Policy also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy at any time and will provide notification of changes by posting the revised Privacy Policy on our website www.birst.com.

This privacy policy covers the site www.birst.com as well as the Birst services.

Birst Inc. has received TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, www.birst.com and the Birst service platform and does not cover information that may be collected from mobile devices. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Birst Inc.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request "Contact TRUSTe").

Birst complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Birst has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Birst’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

Skyhigh Enterprise-Ready cloud services fully satisfy the most stringent requirements for data protection, identity verification, service security, business practices, and legal protection.

Skyhigh Networks performs objective and thorough evaluations of the enterprise-readiness of cloud service based on a detailed set of criteria developed in conjunction with the Cloud Security Alliance (CSA). Services designated as Skyhigh Enterprise-Ready are the services receiving the highest CloudTrust™ Ratings, which fully satisfy the most stringent requirements for data protection, identity verification, service security, business practices, and legal protection.

#### When Information Is Collected

When registering to receive more information or registering for demos, we require users to give us your personal information, such as their name, company name, title, address, phone number, and e-mail address.

When registering for a free or paid account (the “Online Service”), we require users to give us personal information, such as their name, company name, title, address, phone number, and e-mail address. Registered users can update this information at any time by logging into our website and editing their profile.

You can also log in to our site using sign-in services such as an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like this may give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

Customers of the Online Service will be using our website to host data and information (“Hosted Data”). As part of our Online Service, Birst collects information under the direction of its Customers. In this capacity, our Customer is the controller of the data and Birst acts as a data processor. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Customers.

#### How the Collected Information Is Used

Birst uses the information that we collect to set up the Online Service for individuals and their organizations. We may also use the information to contact customers to further discuss customer interest in our company, the Online Service that we provide, and updates and enhancements made to it, as well as to send information regarding our company’s or our partners’ offerings, such as promotions and events. We also use this information to administer our website, improve our Online Service and to communicate with our customers regarding account administration issues. Customer email addresses and any personal customer information will not be distributed or shared with third parties except for the purposes described above. Customers can opt out of receiving any marketing communication by changing their account settings, clicking on the unsubscribe link in the email, emailing us, or at the time the customer registers for the Online Service. We may also track and analyze non-identifying and aggregate usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers.

We use anonymous information about your interaction with our service platform for analytical purposes only. This is done by viewing only aggregated data to help us understand how our services are used.

#### Correcting and Updating Your Personal Information

To review and update your personal information to ensure it is accurate, you can log into your account and update your information under “Account”. Additionally, if you would like to request to have your personal information deleted and discontinued from use, please contact us as described below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable time frame.

We have testimonials on our site. For which the individuals have given permission for us to post their personal information. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [webmaster@birst.com](mailto:webmaster@birst.com "Email webmaster@birst.com").

We also have blog which is managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

For access to the data controlled by our Customers, that Customer will need to be contacted directly with any access requests. If the Customer subsequently requests us to remove the data, we will respond within a reasonable time frame.

Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or by contacting us as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [operations@birst.com](mailto:operations@birst.com "Email operations@birst.com"). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Customer for as long as needed to provide services to our Customer. Birst will retain this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### Community

Our site has a community section where customers can contact and share ideas with other customers. We may share your personal information with other customers in response to your requests and according to your Account privacy settings. You can edit your privacy settings anytime as to who can view your information by editing your profile and changing your preferences. If you think that an unauthorized profile is created without your permission, please contact us to remove/delete such profile at [community@birs](mailto:community@birst.com)t. If you want to delete or deactivate your Community profile, please contact us at [community@birst.com](mailto:community@birst.com).

#### Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Birst. Please be aware that we, Birst, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware that when you leave our site you are subject to the privacy practices of those destination sites; we encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site and service platform.

#### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. Our login page and service platform use TLS encryption. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Customers are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of their user registration and password.

For information about Birst Security practices for our Online Service, please see the [Birst Security and Reliability Whitepaper](http://info.birst.com/Birst-Security-and-Reliability.html).

#### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Birst and our marketing and analytics partners. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. Our cookies are not linked to personal information.

We use cookies for improving user experience, displaying relevant content to users, tracking marketing campaigns, and providing functionality (e.g. Integrating with other software)] Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, and the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

We use Local Storage (LS) such as HTML5 to provide certain features on our site. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity also use LS such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here ](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/ "Targeted Advertising Opt-out USA")(or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/ "Targeted Advertising Opt-out EU")) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

#### Disclosure of Information

The Company does not share, sell, rent, or trade PII with third parties for their promotional purposes.

We may disclose the information we receive:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect
  * if Birst is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

We may also provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as sending you emails or offering you the blog section. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

#### Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the changes taking effect.

#### Questions

Questions regarding Birst Privacy Policy or the practices of our website should be directed to [privacy@birst.com](mailto:privacy@birst.com "Email privacy@birst.com") or by regular mail addressed to:

Birst, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy  
45 Fremont Street, 18th Floor  
San Francisco, CA 94105
